I thought I'd tell you a little about what I like to write.
فكرت انه علي ان اخبركم قليلا عما احب ان اكتب.
And I like to immerse myself in my topics.
واني احب ان انغمس في مواضيعي.
I just like to dive right in and become sort of a human guinea pig.
احب فقط ان اغوص واصبح نوعا من الخنزير البشري.
And I see my life as a series of experiments.
كما اني ارى حياتي سلسلة من التجارب.
So, I work for Esquire magazine, and a couple of years ago,
و بالتالي انا اعمل لصالح مجلة اسكواير. و منذ عامين اثنين
I wrote an article called "My Outsourced Life,"
قد كتبت مقالا بعنوان"العيش بالاستعانة بمصادر خارجية"
where I hired a team of people in Bangalore, India,
حيث وظفت فريقا من الناس في بانغلور بالهند
to live my life for me.
لكي يعيشوا حياتي بدلا عني.
So, they answered my emails.
فاجابوا عن رسائلي الالكترونية.
They answered my phone.
قاموا بالرد على هاتفي.
They argued with my wife for me, and they read my son bedtime stories.
تجادلوا مع زوجتي من اجلي وقرؤوا لابني قصص ما قبل النوم.
It was the best month of my life,
كان الشهر الافضل في حياتي على الاطلاق
because I just sat back and I read books and watched movies.
لاني كنت اجلس وحسب اقرءا الكتب و اشاهد الافلام.
It was a wonderful experience.
كانت تجربة رائعة.
More recently, I wrote an article for Esquire called --
مؤخرا كتبت مقالا لمجلة اسكواير بعنوان
about radical honesty.
النزاهة الجذرية.
And this is a movement where --
وهذه حركة
this is started by a psychologist in Virginia,
قد انشئت من قبل عالم نفساني في فرجينيا
who says that you should never, ever lie,
يقول انه لا يجب ان تكذب ابدا ما حييت
except maybe during poker and golf, his only exceptions.
ما عدا عند لعب الجولف و البوكر.هذه كانت إستثناءاته الوحيدة.
And, more than that, whatever is on your brain
و ما عدا ذلك فكل ما يجول بخاطرك
should come out of your mouth.
يجب ان يقال على لسانك.
So, I decided I would try this for a month.
قررت ان اجرب هذا لمدة شهر.
This was the worst month of my life.
كان هذا الشهر الاسوء في حياتي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I do not recommend this at all.
انا لا انصح بذلك مطلقا.
To give you a sense of the experience,
لكي اعطيكم فكرة عن التجربة
the article was called, "I Think You're Fat."
كان المقال بعنوان "اعتقد انك بدين".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So, that was hard.
كان ذلك صعبا.
My most recent book -- my previous book was called "The Know-It-All,"
كتابي الجديد--كتابي السابق كان بعنوان "العليم"
and it was about the year I spent reading the Encyclopedia Britannica
وكان حول العام الذي امضيته في قراءة الموسوعة البريطانية
from A to Z in my quest to learn everything in the world,
من ألفها إلى يائها سعيا وراء معرفة كل شيء في العالم
or more precisely from Aak, which is a type of East Asian music,
او لكي اكون دقيقا جدا من أ -أك وهي نوع من الموسيقى من شرق اسيا
all the way to Zwyiec, which is -- well, I don't want to ruin the ending.
علي طول الطريق الى زواييك و هي --حسنا لن افسد النهاية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's a very exciting twist ending, like an O. Henry novel, so I won't ruin it.
انها نهاية ملتوية جد مثيرة تشبه رواية بقلم هنري لهذا لن افسدها.
But I love that one,
لكني احببتها
because that was an experiment about how much information
لانها كانت تجربة حول الكم الهائل من المعلومات
one human brain could absorb.
التي يمكن للعقل البشري تقبلها
Although, listening to Kevin Kelly, you don't have to remember anything.
مع ان الاستماع الى كيفن كالي لا يستوجب منك تذكر اي شيئ.
You can just Google it.
فليس عليك الا ان تبحث عنها عبر جوجل.
So, I wasted some time there.
و بالتالي قد اضعت الكثير من الوقت هناك.
I love those experiments,
احب تلك التجارب
but I think that the most profound
لكن اعتقد ان التجربة التي كانت اكثر عمقا و
and life-changing experiment that I've done
ا حدثت تغييرا في حياتي من بين كل التجارب التي مررت بها
is my most recent experiment, where I spent a year
هي احدثها حيث اني امضيت عاما
trying to follow all of the rules of the Bible,
محاولا اتباع كل تعاليم الكتاب المقدس
"The Year of Living Biblically."
"سنة العيش وفق الانجيل"
And I undertook this for two reasons.
ولقد قمت بهذا لسببين اثنين
The first was that I grew up with no religion at all.
السبب اللاول هو اني ترعرعت بدون عقيدة تقريبا
As I say in my book, I'm Jewish in the same way
كما ذكرت في كتابي انا يهودي بنفس طريقة
the Olive Garden is Italian.
أن حديقة الزيتون ايطالية
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So, not very.
ليس كثيرا
But I've become increasingly interested in religion.
و لكني اصبحت مهتما بالدين على نحو متزايد
I do think it's the defining issue of our time,
اعتقد انها القضية التي تعرّف زماننا
or one of the main ones.
او واحدة من اهم القضايا
And I have a son. I want to know what to teach him.
انا لدي ابن و اريد ان اعرف ما علي تعليمه اياه
So, I decided to dive in head first, and try to live the Bible.
لهذا قررت ان اغوص راسا اولا ثم احاول ان احيا حياة الكتاب المقدس
The second reason I undertook this is because
السبب الثاني الذي من اجله قمت بذلك هو
I'm concerned about the rise of fundamentalism,
اني قلق بشان تزايد الاصولية
religious fundamentalism, and people who say
أصوليو الأديان و الناس الذي يقولون انهم
they take the Bible literally, which is, according to some polls,
ياخذون ماجاء في الكتاب المقدس حرفيا وهو حسب بعض الاستفتاءات
as high as 45 or 50 percent of America.
يصل الى 45 او50 بالمائة في امريكا
So I decided, what if you really did take the Bible literally?
فقررت ماذا لو حقا اتبعت الكتاب المقدس حرفيا
I decided to take it to its logical conclusion
قررت ان اصل به الى نتيجته المنطقية
and take everything in the Bible literally,
فاخذت كل شيئ جاء في اللانجيل حرفيا
without picking and choosing.
بدون انتقاء او اختيار
The first thing I did was I got a stack of bibles.
كان اول شيئ فعلته هو الحصول على كومة من الكتب المقدسة
I had Christian bibles.
املك الكتب المقدسة المسيحية
I had Jewish bibles.
املك الكتب المقدسة اليهودية
A friend of mine sent me something called a hip-hop bible,
صديق لي ارسل ا لي شيئا يسمى الكتاب المقدس للهيب هوب
where the twenty-third Psalm is rendered as, "The Lord is all that,"
حيث ان المزمور الثالث و العشرين قدم على انه"الرب هو كل هذا"
as opposed to what I knew it as, "The Lord is my shepherd."
خلافا لما اعرفه عن ان" الرب هو الراعي"
Then I went down and I read several versions,
ثم نزلت و قرات عدة نسخ
and I wrote down every single law that I could find.
و دونت كل قانون استطعت ايجاده
And this was a very long list -- over 700 rules.
و كانت قائمة طويلة جدا- اكثر من سبعمائة قانون
And they range from the famous ones that I had heard of --
وتتراوح بين قوانين مشهورة قد سمعت عنها
The Ten Commandments, love your neighbor, be fruitful and multiply.
الوصايا العشر، حب جارك، كن نافعا وتناسل
So I wanted to follow those.
فاردت ان اتبعها
And actually, I take my projects very seriously,
و في الواقع اخذت مشاريعي على محمل الجد
because I had twins during my year,
لأنه اصبح لدي توأم خلال تلك السنة
so I definitely take my projects seriously.
فقطعا اخذت عملي على محمل الجد
But I also wanted to follow the hundreds
لكن اردت ايضا ان اتبع المئات
of arcane and obscure laws that are in the Bible.
من القوانين الغامضة الواردة في الكتاب المقدس
There is the law in Leviticus,
هناك قانون في سفر اللاويين
"You cannot shave the corners of your beard."
لا يمكنك ان تحلق زوايا لحيتك
I didn't know where my corners were,
لم اكن اعرف اين تكون زوايا لحيتي
so I decided to let the whole thing grow,
فقررت ان اتركها تنمو
and this is what I looked like by the end.
وهذا ما اصبحت ابدو عليه في النهاية.
As you can imagine, I spent a lot of time at airport security.
كما تتخيلون امضيت وقتا طويلا في امن المطار.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
My wife wouldn't kiss me for the last two months.
زوجتي لم تقبلني خلال الشهرين الماضيين.
So, certainly the challenge was there.
بالتاكيد كان التغيير من هناك.
The Bible says you cannot wear clothes made of mixed fibers,
ينص الكتاب المقدس على عدم ارتداء ثياب مصنوعة من نسيج مختلط
so I thought, "Sounds strange, but I'll try it."
ففكرت"يبدو غريبا لكن سوف اجربه"
You only know if you try it.
لا يمكنك ان تعرف الا اذا جربته.
I got rid of all my poly-cotton T-shirts.
تخلصت من جميع قمصاني القطنية.
The Bible says that if two men are in a fight,
يقول الكتاب المقدس انه اذا ما تقاتل رجلان
and the wife of one of those men grabs the testicles of the other man,
ومسكت زوجة احدهما بخصيتي الرجل الاخر
then her hand shall be cut off.
يجب ان تقطع يدها.
So, I wanted to follow that rule.
فاردت ان اتبع هذا القانون.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
That one I followed by default,
لقد اتبعت هذا الاخير تلقائياً
by not getting in a fight with a man whose wife was standing nearby,
بعدم الخوض في عراك مع رجل تقف زوجته جانبا
looking like she had a strong grip.
تبدو كما لو ان لها قبضة قوية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So -- oh, there's another shot of my beard.
اه هناك لقطة اخرى للحيتي.
I will say it was an amazing year
ساقول انها كانت سنة عجيبة
because it really was life changing, and incredibly challenging.
لأنها غيرت حياتي بالاضافة لكونها مصدر تحدي بشكل لايصدق.
And there were two types of laws that were particularly challenging.
وكان هناك نوعان من القوانين مثلا تحديا على وجه الخصوص .
The first was avoiding the little sins that we all commit every day.
الاول كان حول تجنب الصغائر التي نقترفها جميعنا يوميا.
You know, I could spend a year not killing,
تعلمون بمستطاعي ان امضي سنة من غير ان اقتل
but spending a year not gossiping, not coveting, not lying --
لكن قضاء عام بدون نميمة وطمع وكذب--
you know, I live in New York, and I work as a journalist,
تعلمون انا اعيش في نيويورك و اعمل كصحفي
so this was 75, 80 percent of my day I had to do it.
لهذا كان علي ان افعل كل ذلك حوالي 70، 80 بالمائة من يومي.
But it was really interesting, because I was able to make some progress,
و لكن كان ذلك مثيرا للاهتمام لاني استطعت ان احقق بعض التقدم
because I couldn't believe how much
لاني لم استطع ان اصدق كم
my behavior changed my thoughts.
غيّر سلوكي من افكاري.
This was one of the huge lessons of the year,
كان هذا واحد من الدروس الضخمة
is that I almost pretended to be a better person,
كنت تقريبا اتظاهر باني شخص جيد
and I became a little bit of a better person.
و اصبحت شيئا قليلا من شخص جيد.
So I had always thought, you know, "You change your mind,
فكنت افكر دائما تعلمون"تغير رايك
and you change your behavior," but it's often the other way around.
تغير تصرفك" لكن في كثير من الاحيان تكون الطريقة الاخرى.
You change your behavior, and you change your mind.
تغير تصرفك تغير رايك.
So, you know, if you want to become more compassionate,
اذن تعلمون اذا اردت ان تصبح رحيماً جدا
you visit sick people in the hospital,
قم زيارة المرضى في المستشفى
and you will become more compassionate.
و سوف تصبح اكثر رحمة.
You donate money to a cause,
تبرع بالمال من اجل قضية
and you become emotionally involved in that cause.
و سوف تصبح مشتركا عاطفيا في تلك القضية.
So, it really was cognitive psychology --
هكذا كان بحق العلم النفسي اللادراكي
you know, cognitive dissonance -- that I was experiencing.
تعلمون التنافر الادراكي-- كنت اجرب ذلك.
The Bible actually talks about cognitive psychology,
كان الكتاب المقدس في الواقع يتحدث عن علم النفس الإدراكي
very primitive cognitive psychology.
علم النفس الإدراكي البدائي جدا.
In the Proverbs, it says that if you smile, you will become happier,
جاء في الامثال انه اذا ابتسمت سوف تصبح اسعد
which, as we know, is actually true.
و هو كما نعرف في الواقع صحيح.
The second type of rule that was difficult to obey
كان من الصعب تنفيذ النوع الثاني من القانون
was the rules that will get you into a little trouble
وهو قانون سوف يوقعك في القليل من المتاعب
in twenty-first-century America.
قي امريكا القرن الواحد و العشرين.
And perhaps the clearest example of this is stoning adulterers.
وربما اوضح مثال عن ذلك هو رجم الزناة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But it's a big part of the Bible,
لكنه يحتل جزءا كبيرا من الكتاب المقدس
so I figured I had to address it.
فحسبت انه علي ان اشير اليه.
So, I was able to stone one adulterer.
كان بمقدوري ان ارجم زان واحد.
It happened -- I was in the park, and I was dressed in my biblical clothing,
حدث ذلك عندما كنت في المنتزه وكنت حينها مرتديا الثياب التي نص عليها الكتاب المقدس
so sandals and sort of a white robe,
صنادل وثوبا ابيضا
you know, because again, the outer affects the inner.
تعلمون لان الخارج يؤثر على الداخل.
I wanted to see how dressing biblically affected my mind.
اردت ان ارى كيف ان ارتداء ثيابي وفق الكتاب المقدس قد اثر علي فكري.
And this man came up to me and he said,
واتى هذا الرجل و قال
"Why are you dressed like that?"
"لماذ ا ترتدي ملابسا كهذه
And I explained my project,
فشرحت له مشروعي
and he said, "Well, I am an adulterer, are you going to stone me?"
فقال"حسن انا زان هل سترجمني؟"
And I said, "Well, that would be great!"
فقلت"جيد هذا سيكون رائعا!"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I actually took out a handful of stones from my pocket
و اخرجت حفنة من الحجارة من جيبي
that I had been carrying around for weeks,
كنت احملها معي منذ اسابيع
hoping for just this interaction -- and, you know, they were pebbles --
متطلعا لهذا اللقاء--و تعرفون لقد كانت حصى
but he grabbed them out of my hand.
و لكنه انتزعها من يدي.
He was actually an elderly man, mid-70s, just so you know.
في الواقع كان رجلا عجوزا في منتصف السبعينات حتى تعلمون.
But he's still an adulterer, and still quite angry.
و لكنه مايزال زانيا و غاضبا.
He grabbed them out of my hand
انتزعهم من يدي
and threw them at my face, and I felt that I could --
والقى بهم في وجهي وشعرت اني كنت استطيع
eye for an eye -- I could retaliate, and throw one back at him.
العين بالعين كنت استطيع ان انتقم و القي بواحدة عليه
So that was my experience stoning, and it did allow me
كانت هذه تجربتي مع الرجم و قد اتاحت لي
to talk about, in a more serious way, these big issues.
التحدث بجدية عن هذه القضايا الكبرى
How can the Bible be so barbaric in some places,
كيف يمكن ان يكون الكتاب المقدس همجيا جدا في بعض المواطن
and yet so incredibly wise in others?
و لكن جد حكيم في مواطن اخرى
How should we view the Bible?
كيف علينا ان ننظر الى الكتاب المقدس
Should we view it, you know, as original intent,
هل علينا ان ننظر اليه تعلمون
like a sort of a Scalia version of the Bible?
كنوع من نسخة سكاليا من الإنجيل
How was the Bible written?
كيف تم كتابة الإنجيل
And actually, since this is a tech crowd,
و في الواقع و بسبب هذا الزخم للوسائل التقنية الحديثة
I talk in the book about how the Bible actually reminds me
اتحدث في كتابي عن كيف ان الكتاب المقدس يذكرني بالواقع
of the Wikipedia, because it has all of these authors and editors
بالويكيبيديا لما تحتويه من ادباء و محررين
over hundreds of years.
عبر مئات السنين.
And it's sort of evolved.
وهي نوع ما متطورة.
It's not a book that was written and came down from on high.
هي ليست كتاب قد كتب ثم نزل من أعلي.
So I thought I would end by telling you
فكرت ان اختم باخباركم
just a couple of the take-aways, the bigger lessons
فقط زوجين من الدروس العظيمة
that I learned from my year.
هذا ما تعلمته من سنتي.
The first is, thou shalt not take the Bible literally.
اولا يجب ان لا تتبع كل ما جاء في الإنجيل حرفيا.
This became very, very clear, early on.
هذا اصبح واضحا جدا جدا في وقت مبكر.
Because if you do, then you end up acting like a crazy person,
لانه لو فعلت ذلك سينتهي بك المطاف الى التصرف كشخص مجنون
and stoning adulterers, or -- here's another example.
و رجم الزناة او-- اليكم بمثال اخر
Well, that's another. I did spend some time shepherding.
حسنا هذا مثال اخر--امضيت بعض الوقت في رعي الغنم.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's a very relaxing vocation. I recommend it.
انه عمل مريح جدا انا اوصي به.
But this one is -- the Bible says that you cannot touch women
وهو ان الإنجيل قال لا يمكنك ان تلمس النساء
during certain times of the month, and more than that,
في بعض اللاوقات من الشهر و اكثر من ذلك
you cannot sit on a seat where a menstruating woman has sat.
لا يمكنك ان تجلس على كرسي كانت تجلس عليه حائض.
And my wife thought this was very offensive,
واعتقدت زوجتي ان ذلك مهينا جدا
so she sat in every seat in our apartment,
فكانت تجلس على كل كرسي في شقتنا
and I had to spend much of the year standing
و كان علي ان امضي معضم السنة واقفا
until I bought my own seat and carried it around.
حتى اشتريت كرسي الخاص و حملته معي.
So, you know, I met with creationists.
وهكذا تعرفون التقيت بالمؤمنين بخلق الكون.
I went to the creationists' museum.
ذهبت الى معرض المؤمنين بخلق الكون.
And these are the ultimate literalists.
وهؤلاء اخر المطبقين حرفياً.
And it was fascinating, because they were not stupid people at all.
و كان هذا فاتنا لأنهم لم يكونوا اناسا اغبياء على الاطلاق.
I would wager that their IQ is exactly the same as the average evolutionist.
اراهن ان معدل ذكائهم هو تماما نفس معدل ذكاء المؤمنين بالنشوء والتطور
It's just that their faith is so strong
الا ان ايمانهم قوي جدا
in this literal interpretation of the Bible
في هذا التفسير الحرفي للإنجيل
that they distort all the data to fit their model.
يحرفون كل المعلومات لكي تناسب نموذجهم.
And they go through these amazing mental gymnastics to accomplish this.
وهم يقومون بتلك الرياضة العقلية المذهلة لتنفيذ ذلك.
And I will say, though, the museum is gorgeous.
ومع ذلك سوف اقول ان المتحف رائع.
They really did a fantastic job.
لقد قاموا حقا بعمل رائع.
If you're ever in Kentucky,
اذا صادف و ذهبتم الى كنتاكي
there's, you can see a movie of the flood,
هناك يمكنكم مشاهدة فيلم عن الطوفان
and they have sprinklers in the ceiling
كما لديهم مرشات في السقف
that will sprinkle on you during the flood scenes.
سوف ترش عليك خلال مشاهد الطوفان
So, whatever you think of creationism -- and I think it's crazy --
كل ما يمكنكم ان تتخيلوه عن الخلق و اعتقد انه ضرب من الجنون
they did a great job.
لقد قاموا بعمل عظيم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Another lesson is that thou shalt give thanks.
درس اخر وهو ان تقدم صلاة الشكر.
And this one was a big lesson because I was praying,
و هذا درس عظيم لاني كنت اصلي
giving these prayers of thanksgiving, which was odd for an agnostic.
كان اداء صلوات عيد الشكر شيئ غريب بالنسبة لملحد.
But I was saying thanks all the time, every day,
و مع ذلك كنت اقول شكرا كل الاوقات و كل يوم
and I started to change my perspective.
و بدات اغير منظوري
And I started to realize the hundreds of little things
كما بدأت ادرك مئات الأشياء الصغيرة
that go right every day, that I didn't even notice,
التي تمر امامي كل يوم و لا الاحظها
that I took for granted, as opposed to focusing
تلك التي اعتبرتها من المسلمات --في مقابل التركيز
on the three or four that went wrong.
على ثلاثة او اربعة اشياء
So, this is actually a key to happiness for me,
بالتالي كان هذا مفتاح السعادة النسبة لي
is to just remember when I came over here,
مجرد التفكير اني عندما اتيت الى هنا ان
the car didn't flip over, and I didn't trip coming up the stairs.
السيارة لم تنقلب كما اني لم اتعثر عند صعود الدرج
It's a remarkable thing.
هذا امر جدير بالملاحظة
Third, that thou shall have reverence.
ثالثا عليك ان تتحلى بالتبجيل
This one was unexpected because I started the year
كان هذا غير متوقع لاني بدات السنة
as an agnostic, and by the end of the year,
كملحد ومع نهاية السنة
I became what a friend of mine calls a reverent agnostic, which I love.
اصبحت كما يطلق علي صديق لي الملحد الموقر وهو شيئ احبه.
And I'm trying to start it as a movement.
و انا اعمل على بعثها كحركة
So, if anyone wants to join,
لذا فإن أراد اي شخص الإنضمام
the basic idea is, whether or not there is a God,
فالفكرة الأساسية هي ، سواء كان هنالك إله ام لا
there's something important and beautiful about the idea of sacredness,
هناك شئ هام و جميل في فكرة القداسة
and that our rituals can be sacred.
و ان طقوسنا يمكن ان تكون مقدسة
The Sabbath can be sacred.
يوم السبت يمكن ان يكون مقدسا
This was one of the great things about my year, doing the Sabbath,
هذا كان من اروع الاشياء عن سنتي، فعل التقديس،
because I am a workaholic, so having this one day
لاني مجد في عملي والحصول على يوم كهذا
where you cannot work, it really, that changed my life.
لا عمل فيه قد غير حقا حياتي
So, this idea of sacredness, whether or not there is a God.
هذا ما تتمثل فيه فكرة القداسة، سواء كان هنالك إله ام لا
Thou shall not stereotype.
لا يجب ان تضع انماطا
This one happened because
لقد حصل هذا لاني
I spent a lot of time with various religious communities
قضيت وقتا كثيرا مع مجتمعات دينية مختلفة
throughout America because I wanted it to be more
عبر امريكا لاني رغبت فيها اكثر
than about my journey.
من رحلتي.
I wanted it to be about religion in America.
اردت أن تكون عن الدين في أمريكا
So, I spent time with evangelical Christians, and Hasidic Jews, and the Amish.
لهذا قضيت وقتا مع المسيحيين الانجيليين و اليهود الحسيديين وطائفة الآمش
I'm very proud because
انا فخور جدا لأني
I think I'm the only person in America
اعتقد ا اني الشخص الوحيد في امريكا
to out Bible-talk a Jehovah's Witness.
الذي تكلم عن الإنجيل في حضرة جيهوفا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
After three and a half hours, he looked at his watch,
بعد ثلاث ساعاث و نصف نظر الى ساعته
he's like, "I gotta go."
كما لو انه يقول علي ان اذهب
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Oh, thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا
Thank you. Bless you, bless you.
شكرا فليباركك فليباركك الرب
But it was interesting
كان مثيرا للإهتمام
because I had some very preconceived notions about, for instance,
لانه كان لدي بعض الافكار المسبقة على سبيل المثال عن
evangelical Christianity, and I found that
المسيحيين الإنجيليين ولقد وجدت
it's such a wide and varied movement
انها حركة واسعة و متنوعة
that it is difficult to make generalizations about it.
حتى انه من الصعب التعميم
There's a group I met with called the Red Letter Christians,
التقيت بمجموعة تسمى مسيحيو الرسالة الحمراء
and they focus on the red words in the Bible,
و هم يركزون على الكلمات الحمراء الواردة في الإنجيل
which are the ones that Jesus spoke.
تلك التي قالها يسوع
That's how they printed them in the old Bibles.
هذه هي الطريقة اللتي كانوا ينسخونها في الإنجيل.
And their argument is that Jesus never talked about homosexuality.
و كانت حجتهم ان يسوع لم يتكلم ابدا عن المثلية الجنسية.
They have a pamphlet that says,
لديهم منشور يقول
"Here's what Jesus said about homosexuality,"
هذا ما قاله يسوع عن المثلية
and you open it up, and there's nothing in it.
و عندما تفتحه لا تجد فيه شيئا;
So, they say Jesus did talk a lot about helping the outcasts,
هم يقولون ان اليسوع قد تحدث بإسهاب عن مساعدة المنبوذين
helping poor people.
ومساعدة الفقراء
So, this was very inspiring to me.
و كان هذامصدر إلهام بالنسبة لي
I recommend Jim Wallis and Tony Campolo.
اقترح جيم والس و طوني كمبولو.
They're very inspiring leaders, even though I disagree
إنهما زعيمان ملهمان رغماً عن اني اختلف
with much of what they say.
مع الكثير مما يقولانه;
Also, thou shalt not disregard the irrational.
ايضا لايمكنك تجاهل الغير منطقي;
This one was very unexpected because, you know,
هذا كان غير متوقعا بشدة لأنه كما تعلمون
I grew up with the scientific worldview,
ترعرعت في كنف النظرة العلمية
and I was shocked learning how much of my life
و لقد صدمت لمعرفة ان معظم حياتي
is governed by irrational forces.
مسيرة بقوى غير منطقية;
And the thing is, if they're not harmful,
و الامر هو انه اذا كانت غير مؤذية
they're not to be completely dismissed.
فلا يجب ان ترفض;
Because I learned that -- I was thinking, I was
لاني تعلمت ان --كنت افكر اني
doing all these rituals, these biblical rituals,
كنت اقوم بكل تلك الطقوس، طقوس الكتاب المقدس
separating my wool and linen, and I would ask these religious people
فصل الصوف و الكتان، كنت سأسأل رجال الدين
"Why would the Bible possibly tell us to do this? Why would God care?"
لماذا يأمرنا الكتاب المقدس بفعل ذلك ؟ لماذا سيهتم الرب؟
And they said, "We don't know,
فيقولون لا نعرف
but it's just rituals that give us meaning."
انها مجرد طقوس تمنحنا معنى
And I would say, "But that's crazy."
وكنت ساقول "ولكن هذا جنون"
And they would say, "Well, what about you?
وسوف يقولون"حسناً، ماذا عنك"
You blow out candles on top of a birthday cake.
أنت تطفئ شموعا فوق كعكة عيد ميلاد
If a guy from Mars came down and saw, here's one guy
اذا نزل شاب من المريخ و رأى، ها هو شخص
blowing out the fire on top of a cake
يشعل النار فوق الكعكة
versus another guy not wearing clothes of mixed fabrics,
بالمقابل شاب اخر لا يلبس ثيابا مصنوعة من نسيج مختلط
would the Martians say, 'Well, that guy, he makes sense,
هل سيقول المريخي "جيد هذا الشاب عاقل
but that guy's crazy?'"
ولكن ذلك الشاب مجنون؟"
So no, I think that rituals are, by nature, irrational.
لا فانا اعتقد ان الطقوس بطبيعتها غير منطقية
So the key is to choose the right rituals,
اذا فالسر هو ان نختار الطقوس الصحيحة
the ones that are not harmful -- but rituals by themselves
تلك التي ليست مؤذية-- الطقوس في حد ذاتها
are not to be dismissed.
لا يتم رفضها.
And finally I learned that thou shall pick and choose.
و في النهاية تعلمت انه يجب ان تنتقي و تختار.
And this one I learned because
و لقد تعلمت هذا لأني
I tried to follow everything in the Bible.
حاولت ان اتبع كل ما جاء في الإنجيل.
And I failed miserably.
و لقد فشلت فشلا ذريعا.
Because you can't.
لأنك لا تقدر.
You have to pick and choose. And anyone who follows the Bible
عليك ان تنتقي و تختار و كل من يتبع الإنجيل
is going to be picking and choosing.
سوف ينتقي و يختار.
The key is to pick and choose the right parts.
السر هو ان تنتقي و تختار الأجزاء الصحيحة.
There's the phrase called cafeteria religion,
هناك عبارة تسمى كافيتريا الدين
and the fundamentalists will use it in a denigrating way,
و الأصوليون سوف يستعملونها بطريقة تشوه السمعة
and they'll say, "Oh, it's just cafeteria religion.
و سوق يقولون "أوه ، إنها ليست سوى كافيتريا الدين"
You're just picking and choosing."
فأنت فقط تنتقي و تختار
But my argument is, "What's wrong with cafeterias?"
و لكن حجتي هي "ما العيب في الكافيتريات ؟"
I've had some great meals at cafeterias.
تناولت بعض الوجبات الرائعة في الكافيتريات.
I've also had some meals that make me want to dry heave.
كما اني تناولت بعض الوجبات التي جعلتني ارغب في التقيؤ.
So, it's about choosing the parts of the Bible about compassion,
لذا، فالأمر حول اختيار الاجزاء المتعلقه بالرحمة من الإنجيل
about tolerance, about loving your neighbor,
حول التسامح ، و محبة جارك
as opposed to the parts about homosexuality is a sin,
كنقيض للأجزاء حول أن المثلية هي خطيئة،
or intolerance, or violence,
التعصب، أو العنف
which are very much in the Bible as well.
التي وردت بكثافة في الإنجيل أيضاً.
So if we are to find any meaning in this book,
لهذا اذا كنا سنبحث عن اي معنى في هذا الكتاب
then we have to really engage it, and wrestle with it.
علينا اذن ان نلج اليه و نتصارع معه.
And I thought I'd end with just a couple more.
وفكرت اني ساختم باكثر من زوجين.
There's me reading the Bible.
هذا أنا اقرء الإنجيل.
That's how I hailed taxicabs.
هذه هي الطريقة التي الوح بها لسيارة الاجرة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Seriously, and it worked. And yes,
انا اتكلم بجد ولقد نجحت --و نعم
that was actually a rented sheep,
لقد كان في الواقع قطيع من الغنم قد استأجرته
so I had to return that in the morning, but it served well for a day.
فكان علي أن أعيده عند الصباح.
So, anyway, thank you so much for letting me speak.
على كل حال شكرا جزيلا للسماح لي بالتحدث.